RG 115, Northwest Child Welfare Club
Connecticut State Library
Northwest Child Welfare Club records
1914-1959
Connecticut State Library
Northwest Child Welfare Club (Hartford, Conn.)
1.25 cubic feet
Originally organized as the Mothers Neighborhood Circle, it became the Northwest Child Welfare Club in 1936. The Club attempted to “promote child welfare in home, school, church and community... raise standards of home life... secure adequate laws for the care and protection of women and children.”
RG115
T001449
Historical Note
Originally organized as the Mothers Neighborhood Circle, it became the Northwest Child Welfare Club in 1936. The Club attempted to “promote child welfare in home, school, church and community... raise standards of home life... secure adequate laws for the care and protection of women and children.” In 1959, they agreed to disband, feeling their work had been successfully taken over by private organizations such as the Parent Teacher Association (PTA), and the state in the form of aid to dependent children and workmen’s compensation.
Scope and Content
Records include meeting minutes, financial records, directories and programs, and a card file of member names and addresses.
Related Material
None.
Index Terms
Organizations:
Northwest Child Welfare Club (Hartford, Conn.); Mothers Neighborhood Circle (Hartford, Conn.)
Subjects:
Northwest Child Welfare Club (Hartford, Conn.) -- Records and correspondence; Mothers Neighborhood Circle (Hartford, Conn.) -- Records and correspondence; Clubs -- Connecticut -- Hartford; Women -- Connecticut -- Hartford -- Societies and clubs
Document Types:
Financial records; Correspondence; Programs; Bank books; Minutes; Membership lists
Restrictions on Access
See the policy.
Container List
- Records, 1914-1959
  - 1. Minutes of regular and board meetings, 1914-1927, 1934-1959; 4 volumes + 4 folders (Box 1)
    - 1914 May 5-1919 January 7, 1 volume (Box 1)
    - 1919 February 4-1922 June 6, 1 volume (Box 1)
    - 1922 September 12-1927 April 12, 1 volume (Box 1)
    - 1934 January 8-1935 June 4, 1 volume (Box 1)
    - 1935 June 4-1959, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - 2. Financial records, 1935-1959; 4 volumes (Box 2)
    - 1935-1942 May, 1 volume (Box 2)
    - 1942 June-1946 April, 1 volume (Box 2)
    - 1946 May-1958 May, 1 volume (Box 2)
    - 1958 June-1959 June, 1 volume (Box 2)
  - 3. Directories and programs, 1931-1959; 27 items (Box 2)
  - 4. Constitution, 1936, undated; 2 items (Box 2)
  - 5. Bank book, 1940-1959 (Box 2)
  - 6. Special guarantee contract, 1918; shared folder (Box 2)
  - 7. Incoming correspondence from the National Society for Broader Education, 1918-1919; shared folder (Box 2)
  - 8. Card file of members names and addresses (Box 3)